Chapter 2

"Welcome," the young woman said with a smile. She was maybe twenty and had that 'first time staffer' look—still excited and bouncy about meeting 'real scientists, by gosh!' Nancy gave her about two days of working at a symposium this size before she too joined the ranks of the weary and cynical.

"Thanks," Nancy said, forcing herself to smile in reply. She was working on about three hours of sleep so the smile was definitely pasted on. There had been too much to do getting ready for this thing; why in all the blazing pits of firey hell did they give only two weeks of notice? Did they have any idea how hard it was to arrange the time, get someone to cover your lab, gather all your research notes that might possibly be relevant to something with as bizzarely broad a mandate as this thing, organize them into a format for sharing, and— She breathed out, forcing herself to let go of the irritation.

"I'm Nancy Keller and these are my staff, Jason and Lorraine," she said, gesturing to the two excited grad students behind her. "We're really bushed—do you have rooms for us?"

"Absolutely!" chirped Flopsy, or Muffin, or whatever the hell her name was. "The conference is in the Room of Requirement over in Hogwarts, and so are your rooms. It's just a quick pop through the Floo and there will be someone to take your bags and bring you to the conference room. Here, let me show you!"

She bounced to her feet with irritatingly energetic brightness and started to lead them towards a roaring fireplace big enough to roast an ox. Nancy could feel the heat from three feet away. There was a table set up next to it with a large jar of glittery silver dust.

"Here you go!" she burbled. "Just take a pinch of Floo powder, throw it into the fire, step in and say 'Hogwarts' nice and loud and you'll be there in a bounce. Oh, and don't forget to keep your elbows in and get out at the first grate. You wouldn't want to end up in Wales like that last fellow." Her smile was bright and shiny and Nancy just wanted to smack her.

"I don't know what your problem is, young lady," she said in her best make-the-new-intern-wet-himself voice. "Whatever it might be, I am not interested in self-immolating today. Tell us where the hell the conference is and stop wasting our time."

Babs looked horrified. "Oh, right, I'm sorry. Professor McGonagall warned me about this, but I forgot. 'Miranda,' she said, 'the Muggles don't know anything about magic so they aren't going to understand that the Floo is safe, so make sure you show them.' I'm so sorry! Here, I'll go first." She grabbed a pinch of the green dust and threw it in the fire, making it roar up and turn bright green. She stepped in without a care in the world and called out "Hogwarts!" She twirled around for a moment as though she were being spun on a record player, and then vanished with a pop.

Nancy blinked.

"Cool," said Lorraine, pushing her Coke-bottle glasses up her nose. Jason gave one of his braying laughs but didn't say anything.

A moment later, Fluffy—no, Miranda—came twirling back through the fire and stepped out in front of them, brushing a bit of ash off her robes.

"See?" she said.

Nancy forced herself not to growl at Mopsy—damnit, Miranda! It wasn't the kid's fault...probably. Maybe.

"Are you seriously expecting us to step into a goddamn fire just because you have some tric—"

"It's probably fine, ma'am," Lorraine said calmly. "Here, let me try." She grabbed a pinch of the powder, threw it in the flames, and stepped in. "Hogwarts!" she called. With a quick spin she was gone.

She reappeared a few seconds later, rubbing her left elbow. "It's fine," she said. "She wasn't kidding about keeping your elbows in, though. Ow."

Nancy glared at her for a moment but grabbed her roller bag, threw the powder in, and stepped into the suddenly-green flames. "Hogwarts!" she growled. The world twirled around her like it had that one time she dropped acid in grad school. It wasn't any more pleasant this time around.

She was spinning through a cyclone of green fire; something she couldn't see smacked her elbow, making her funnybone shriek and her arm go numb. Up ahead she saw a fireplace grill; she quickly pushed herself to the side and stepped into the grill as she whirled by.

She stepped out of another fireplace in what was either a medieval castle or a really good impession of one. She stopped to look around and stumbled when Lorraine came spinning out of the fireplace and smacked into her. Jason came along a moment later.

"That. Was. Awesome!" Jason said, eyes shining like little stars. "Man, I love this wizarding thing!"

A red-headed teenager in a black robe and a serious expression stepped forward. "Hello, Dr Keller. I'm Percy Weasley, Head Boy of Hogwarts. You're just in time for the introductory meeting. Let me have your bags taken—Twirlmott!" A weird creature appeared with a crack! and a puff of smoke. It was only a couple feet tall, and it looked like a stick figure with a wrinkly potato head the size of a beachball, ears you could use for parachutes, and eyes like something out of one of those anime that Jason liked so much.

"Yes, sir?" the little creature asked. It sounded like it had been sucking on helium.

"Twirlmott, please take our guests' bags," Percy said with a polite nod. "They'll be staying in the Room of Requirement, the version with the '37' on the door."

Twirlmott nodded, grabbed all the luggage, and vanished with a pop! before Nancy could say 'no, wait, stop!'

Percy smiled and nodded to himself as though pleased at how smoothly things were going. "If you'll follow me," he began, "I'll take you to the introductory meeting. I think you'll find it qute interesting."

David Martinson was barely in the door when his fourteen-year-old son came barreling into the room with a creature of myth and legend on his shoulder.

"Look dad! He followed me home, can we keep him?" Joel asked, grinning impishly at the stereotype.

David looked at the phoenix consideringly.

"I don't know son," he said gravely. "A firebird is an awfully big responsibility. You'd have to feed him and clean his cage—oof!" He braced himself as his son hugged him, laughing at the mutual joke.

"Okay, where did he come from?" David asked, kicking his suitcase aside with distracted ease. "Does he have a name? I'm guessing he's something to do with those British wizards I was reading about?"

Joel nodded. "I think so, yes. He's smart, and he can kinda-sorta talk, but he communicates mostly in images. Peri, can you tell Dad about yourself?"

fire | primoridal | heart | light | eternal | courage | endless | inspiration | partner-friend-protector

David stumbled and sat down on the couch. "Wow. That was intense." He looked at the bird with new respect. "Okay, so he's intelligent and can communicate, although not in words." He paused. "I really don't know what to ask at this point." He thought about it. "You called him Peri?"

"Yep. Short for 'Hyperion'," Joel said.

David nodded. "Titan of Wisdom, Watchfulness, and the Light, and father of Helios the Sun. Yes, that fits. Glad to see you still remember those old stories." He smiled, remembering the many hours of reading myths and legends and science fiction and fantasy to a much younger Joel at night. At the time, David had had to do a lot of traveling for work, and it tended to show itself by him falling asleep in the middle of a page.

"And then Bilbo said...the plane...needs toothpaste...check oil light..."

"Dad, Dad, that's not what it says!"

"Huh? Oh, right, sorry. And then Bilbo said 'I'm old, Gandalf. I know I don't look it but I'm beginning to feel it in my heart.'"

David smiled a little mistily. Those had been good years; Mary had still been with them then. Ten years, and he still missed her every day.

With a quick cough he brought his attention back to the present. "So, a firebird. No, wait, a phoenix. The Times had that interview with that British girl who was talking to their space agency, she called it a phoenix. Okay, so, why is he here?"

Joel shrugged. "I don't know. I was upstairs last night watching the Perseids and he showed up. I'd been...thinking about wanting to go to the stars, and he asked me if I really meant it. I think that's what he's here for, is to help with that."

"There are two phoenixes known to exist right now, and both of them want to be part of the space effort?" David asked, caught somewhere between surprise and disbelief. "Where were they the past twenty years when we were busy giving up on space travel?"

Peri reared up, flaring his wings wide, threw his head back and sang. The song poured out like liquid light: a challenge, a battle cry, a demand that they rise to their highest, that they fulfill all of the promises they'd made to themselves, undo all the compromises, face up to and, more importantly, overcome their own faults instead of pushing them off on others. It reached into both of them and called forth the fiercest, purest essence of themselves and pointed it at the battle.

When the song stopped, David fell back into his own skin; the world seemed darker...although, perhaps not as dark as it had been before, now that he had the memory of phoenix song. That memory echoed deep within him, plucking on all the strings of hope and dreams that he'd tucked away in order to make room for school and a job and bills and taxes and all the other myriad mundane details of life. It was too late for many of his dreams, but he could help Joel to achieve his. After all, wasn't that what fathers did?

He rubbed his chin thoughtfully, trying to figure out how to do that. "All right...if the goal is to get to space, then we could get in touch with NASA. Or, I suppose we could go up the chain and talk to someone in government—I'm not sure who would be best, though. And I don't really want to end up with reporters camped on the porch, so let's try to keep a lid on this for now. Or...hm. Let me get that article, I'm sure they said something about phoenixes, but I don't remember what. First thing we'll need is to know more about Peri and what he wants from us."

"Has anyone compiled a list of all this stuff?" Fred asked.

Nancy shrugged. "Dunno, I only got here a couple hours ago. First thing I saw was a woman who I swear was Mrs Piggle-Wiggle pushing a cart of candy around, including some frogs made out of chocolate that kept trying to hop away. Over at the bar they were filling the water pitchers with a swishy wand and some bad Latin, and some of the drinks were doing swan dives into themselves. A few feet away from that I watched this Scottish woman turn into a cat—a small cat, so goodbye conservation of mass—and about a minute later some guy in a paisely bathrobe turned a marble into a magpie."

Fred frowned. "Why a marble and a magpie? Was he just into alliteration?"

She shrugged. "I asked him that very same question and he said 'Why a magpie? Because I'm bollocks at parakeets.'" She shook her head in disbelief. "I'm glad you're here, Fred. This is a little weird for me; it's nice to have a familiar face around."

Fred smiled and was just starting to open his mouth when a young boy tapped him on the arm.

"Excuse me, Doctors Blaise and Keller?" he asked politely.

"Yes?" Fred asked curiously.

"I'm Harry Potter. Welcome to the symposium. How have you found it?"

"Oh, it was easy," Fred said casually. "I just got off the Portkey and there it was."

Harry blinked. Nancy sighed.

"Kid, where's your dad?" Nancy asked. She didn't do kids. "I'm assuming he was the Harry Potter who sent the invites?"

Harry frowned and took a breath. "No, Doctor Keller. I was the one who organized this symposium. I need to find a way to do ultra-fast healing, age reversion, and a full-spectrum disease cure. We already have a means to prevent death regardless of injury or age, we just need to solve the eternal youth and health part."

"You need, huh?" she said. Christ. Wizards, and now a kid organizing things. Yeah, right. "How old are you, anyway? Nine? Ten?"

Harry's face got cold. "Twelve," he said, clearly hanging on to the shreds of his temper.

"Nancy..." Fred said. "Maybe go easy? Things are weird here, maybe they have some kind of instantaneous education or something? Or maybe he's like the Merlin from legend, he ages backwards or something?"

Harry's face got even colder. "You are in error, Doctor. I am, in fact, twelve years old. I am also the son of an Oxford professor, I have read the Feynman lectures, can do calculus, and, quite frankly, I probably know more about psychology and the function of the brain than both of you put together. I also break physics on an hourly basis and defeated a Dark Lord—not once but twice—was the first one ever to destroy a Dementor, was the one who figured out that Dementors are simply the shadow of Death, was a major participant in the effort to destroy every Dementor during that unpleasantness a few weeks ago, and was the person who instigated a serious effort at curing Death and illness. A job, I might add, which neither of you has seen fit to do, despite working in biogerontology for longer than I've been alive. I would appreciate it if the two of you would stop automatically treating me like a child and actually use your brains."

Hot rage boiled up Nancy's throat. "Look, you snot-faced little—"

Fred placed a hand on her arm; she glared at him but stopped talking.

"All right, Mr. Potter," he said. "You're an adult in a child's body and you have a significant list of achievements. Why were you coming over to us?"

Harry's voice was icy cold and precise; he seemed at least as angry as Nancy. "I would like to introduce you to Mr. Throgwattle and Professor Slughorn. Mr. Throgwattle is a senior med-wizard at Saint Mungo's, which is the best hospital in wizarding Britain. Professor Slughorn is undisputedly the best potion master in Britain and quite possibly in the world. I suspect the four of you will have some very interesting discussions. Also, you should be aware of the laboratory facilities; this is the Room of Requirement, and it takes whatever form is desired, and supplies whatever facilities are needed. Simply step out the door, tell the receptionist what you need, and he'll open it to an appropriate lab."

"Thank you, Mr. Potter," Fred said with a polite nod. "Please, lead the way. By the way, we were wondering if anyone has compiled a list of all this magic stuff and everything it can do?"

Harry snorted, not even bothering to turn and look at them as he led them across the room. "Has anyone compiled a list of this science stuff and everything it can do? This school spends seven years teaching a functional level of magical knowledge, and there isn't enough time to study every subject. However, you can pick up a briefing packet at the door; there was a delay and they didn't arrive on time or you would have been given one on the way in.

"The things I think you should be most immediately aware of are Invigoration Draught, Wit-Sharpening Potion, Liquid Luck, and Polyjuice. You'll find descriptions of them in the packets but they are, respectively, a powerful stimulant, a nootropic, a guarantee of successful action, and something that will turn you into another person. The advantages of intelligence enhancement and guaranteed luck should be obvious; I had thought that perhaps Polyjuice could be modified to turn you into a younger or uninjured version of yourself." He led them around a knot of people eagerly discussing the opportunity for using False Memory Charms and Legilimency to exchange knowledge from mind-to-mind. Pushing through a last bit of crowd he brought them to two men who were leaning on the wall and sipping drinks.

"Professor Slughorn, Mister Throgwattle, I'd like to introduce Doctors Keller and Blaise," Harry said, nodded politely. "They are experts on life extension from the Muggle side of things. I think the four of you will have a great deal to discuss. Excuse me." He turned and vanished into the crowd.

"Okay, can you get it to take the—"

"She."

"Excuse me?"

"She's a girl. Well, no, phoenixes are actually immortal and don't reproduce so they don't really have genders. Still, I think of her as a girl, and her name is Xare. Please don't call her 'it.' And she's just as intelligent as we are; you can talk to her directly."

Patrick "call me Pat" Halligan rubbed his forehead, hard, as though trying to push the ache out. He'd been a systems engineer at the Space Agency for ten years, and Chief Engineer of Life Support Systems for three; he was used to dealing with problems, but he was having a lot of them today. The idea of talking seriously about sending a twelve-year-old girl into the single most lethal environment known to man—i.e., outer space—without any protection aside from a suit, was probably the biggest problem. The fact that the laws of physics were really more like polite suggestions was another—actually, maybe that one was bigger, he wasn't sure. The fact that he was sitting opposite the aforementioned-twelve-year-old girl and she had a flaming creature of myth on her shoulder which was actually on fire, right now! yet wasn't burning anything...and apparently the thing had human-level intelligence and he was supposed to engage it in conversation... He pulled the bottle of Tylenol out of his desk drawer and knocked four back. Screw recommended doses, this day was just getting more painful by the minute.

"Okay, fine. Xare, sorry about this but if you're going to be involved in experiments that could kill someone, then I really need to check. You're actually fully intelligent? Like, self-aware?"

Caw!

He sighed. "Right. Maybe, maybe not, but you can't speak English."

"She said yes, sir," Hermione offered.

He really hoped the Tylenol would kick in soon. "Okay, good. Let's try something else. Can you read?"

Caw!

"No, sir, she can't," Hermione said.

He rubbed his head again. "Okay, something else then." He pulled three variously-colored pens out of his breast pocket and set them on the desk in a careful line. "Xare, would you please touch the red pen, then the blue one, then the red one again, and then the green one?"

The phoenix gave him a rather old-fashioned look, but it—she! remember the she!—hopped over to the desk and tapped a claw on the indicated pens.

"Huh." He stared at the bird for a moment. So, this is what first contact with an alien species felt like. Well, not really first contact, since apparently these 'wizards' had known about them for years. Still, first contact for him. "Okay, how's your grasp on math? Can you tap your claw two plus three times?"

The phoenix cocked its head at him in confusion.

Sigh. "Okay, no grasp on math," he said. "I suppose that's something that immortal birds made out of fire don't really need. This should be jolly fun."

"Do you really need her to do math, sir?" the girl asked. "You and I can do the math, but don't we just need to know if she can get somewhere?"

Pat shrugged. "I suppose." He shuffled through his folder for a minute and passed over an 8x10. "Okay, uh, Xare, this is a picture of Mare Imbrium. Could you go there based on the picture?"

The phoenix looked at the picture, then hopped back onto Hermione's shoulder and craned her head around to look at her human.

"We need to be able to get there, Xare," her mistress said firmly. "It's important. Everyone, everywhere may depend on it—far more people than the Dementors could ever have killed are at risk if magic and science are mixed and someone decides to use them for evil. We need to have a base somewhere else, so that at least some people can survive. Could you do it? Could you take me there?" Hermione picked up the picture and held it up in front of the bird, looking from Xare to the picture and back.

Caw! the phoenix said. There was a blast of fire and bird and girl were gone.

Author's Footnote: I have a mailing list! It can be found at bit. do /dks-list. There is one email every two weeks, and each one includes links to new postings as well as bonus material not available on the web—world history, character studies, deleted scenes, etc.

Also, I have other stories for sale! You can find them over on 'davidstorrs. com'. I've listed the current catalogue and the current prices below; obviously they may have changed if you're reading this long after I posted it.

"The Draugar War: Opening Salvo" ($1.99), fantasy, novella. It's a spinoff from my story, 'The Two Year Emperor'; High Marshal Albrecht Löfgren arrives for a simple troop inspection but ends up having to lie to High Command, pretend to kill several thousand legionnaires, and—oh yes—fight off the end of the world. Ah well, looks like it's Tuesday.

"One Hot Night" ($0.99), fantasy, novelette. A spinoff from my story 'The Two Year Emperor' in which Ingfred wheels, deals, and cons his way into walking through a legal loophole so that he can make a a fortune selling his memories to a tabloid...and then the law catches up to him.

"Baby Blues" ($1.99), rational horror, novella. Mitchell has escaped from Rikers Island and is desperate to reunite with his daughter, but it's not going to be easy; Rikers is no ordinary prison, Mitchell is no ordinary prisoner, and every human in the city is desperate to get him back behind bars...

"Pay Attention" ($1.99), rational horror, novella. Pay attention. Don't touch the ouija board again. Don't let yourself be distracted. You can keep your mind as long as you don't get distracted. Stay focused. Stay alert. And, whatever you do, pay attention.

Chapter 3

Caw! the phoenix said. There was a blast of fire and bird and girl were gone.

"Holy crap!" Pat yelled, leaping to his feet so fast his chair went flying. Once upright he froze...what could he actually do? The girl wasn't here anymore, and he didn't have any way to bring her back. Should I call her parents? he thought, panic rising up his throat. Who else? Is there anyone who could get her back? She's got maybe thirty seconds, who can I call?! The universe seemed to freeze around him as he dithered, trying to force his brain to come up with the solution to an insoluble problem while the last seconds of Hermione's life ticked past.

With a loud bamf and a flash of fire, bird and girl were back. Hermione hit the floor like a brick.

"MEDIC!" Pat bellowed, his Royal Air Force training yanking him into familiar habits. "I've got a girl down!" Doors slammed open in the hall and feet came pounding towards him; he didn't wait, but dropped to his knees to look Hermione over.

Coo, said the bird, waddling forward to lay its cheek on Hermione's head, its eyes glistening with gathering tears. Pat pushed the creature away, hard. He needed to see how badly Hermione was hurt, and he didn't need some damn bird getting in the way.

He turned Hermione over carefully, giving her a quick check for obvious injuries. Judging from her gasping, raspy breathing, she'd held her breath—the instinctive reaction, and exactly the wrong thing to do in vacuum. Her lungs had clearly taken damage, possibly a full rupture, but there was no easy way to tell exactly how bad it was without equipment and training he didn't have. She was pawing clumsily at her eyes; he pulled her hands away and looked. The water in her eyes had flash-boiled away in vacuum, leaving the eyeballs dry and cracked. The inside of her nose was probably the same way.

Her body was warm, but she was shivering; a quick glance showed that her hands were badly frostbitten, the skin waxy and blackened, and the rubber soles of her trainers were frozen and cracked. With no convection to carry heat away, the vacuum on the Moon wouldn't have been cold on her exposed skin, but Mare Imbrium must have been on the dark side at the time, and the surface would have been several hundred degrees below zero. Heat had conducted out of her soles at lightning speed, freezing and cracking the rubber soles. She must have fallen from the shock and put her hands out to catch herself. Fortunately, she hadn't been there more than fifteen or twenty seconds; hopefully the shoes had protected her feet long enough that she wouldn't lose them to frostbite. There was a pretty good chance she would lose her hands, though.

People were boiling in the door. Pat looked up, his face frozen in horror. "I showed her a picture of the Moon," he said blankly. "She asked the bird if it could take her there, and it did. She's ripped up; we need to get her to a hospital, fast."

John, the head of Power Systems, nodded crisply, dropping to his knees beside them and opening up the first-aid kit he was clutching in one hand. "Alex, go call 911 and get an ambulance here," he said, voice clipped as he focused on the problem at hand. "Bill, call the base doctor and get her up here, fast. The rest of you, out. We need room." A former Sergeant Major in the Marines, he still had the habit of command; everyone jumped to obey.

The bird—Xare—was back, again trying to lay its head on Hermione's. Pat turned on it in a rage, backhanding it hard into the wall. "GET THE HELL AWAY FROM HER!" he bellowed. "This is your fault!"

Caw! it challenged, mantling and disappearing in a flash of fire to reappear standing on Hermione's chest. The thing was only the size of a falcon, but the wing that it struck him with hit like a rhino and sent him tumbling. Before Pat could get back up or John could interfere, it leaned down, its tears spilling into Hermione's eyes.

Right in front of them, the damage vanished. Hermione's eyes were fixed first, the cracks disappearing and a healthy wetness taking their place. The tears continued to fall, and a few moments later her breathing evened out and she reached up, her hands stroking Xare gently. As she did, the flesh of her hands softened back into a healthy pink and the shivering stopped.

Everyone froze in shock.

Hermione sighed and sat up, hugging Xare to her chest. "Let's not do that again," she said shakily. Xare cooed apologetically and bumped her head up under Hermione's chin.

"This place is amazing," Aubrey said, looking around the immense conference room admiringly. "Not just the room, the whole castle. I think I annoyed my guide a great deal because I had to stop and talk to the portraits—and then the moving staircases and the hallway where you end up walking on what used to be the ceiling when you started out...just incredible. How long has it been here, anyway?"

Dumbledore's eyes sparkled behind the half-moon glasses. He stroked his long white beard, hiding a smile behind it. "About two weeks," he said casually.

Aubry goggled. "Two weeks?!" he gasped. "This place is obviously old—there's no way it's only been here two weeks."

"I assure you, two weeks," Dumbledore said gravely. "The original Hogwarts was centuries old, but it was destroyed by a nuclear bomb a short time ago. We only rebuilt it...hm." His eyes went distant for a moment as he calculated. "Fifteen days ago. So, I suppose you're right—not two weeks. It took almost a hundred of us working together for a week to do something the four Founders did overnight. Still, we finished it just fifteen days ago." The smile was now plainly visible on the old wizard's face.

Aubrey stroked the beard that spilled halfway down his chest, eyeing Dumbledore. Eventually, he nodded. "Fine," he said, accepting but still seeming nervous. "Just, please tell me this isn't the original site? If so, the radiation..."

Dumbledore's briefly looked disappointed; clearly, he'd been winding Aubrey up just a little bit and hoping for more of a reaction. "Yes, it's the original site. Don't worry, though—we got rid of the radiation. It was time-consuming, but not difficult."

Aubrey blinked. "You got rid of the radiation." He blinked again. "From a nuclear bomb."

Dumbledore smiled; this was more like it! "Yes, we did. Mr. Potter spoke to the Queen and brought in some Muggles in odd suits with..." He paused, reaching for a word. "Geiger counters. They located the areas that were afflicted with radiation. We placed ward charms around them to keep the effects contained until they could be dealt with, then we went around to each spot and Transfigured the earth to cleanse it."

Aubrey frowned. "I thought science wasn't something that wizards knew about? How did you ward against radiation if you don't know what it is?"

"It took some discussion, but eventually the Muggles were able to explain that this 'radiation' comes in two forms—solid particles and light," Dumbledore explained. "There is a combination of spells—Protego Maxima, Fianto Duri, Repello Inimicum—that create very secure shields around an area. Anything attempting to pass through the shield is disintegrated. We tested it with a geiger counter; it's quite able to destroy the particle-based forms of radiation, and a simple Invisibility charm can stop light from passing through an area in one direction; we simple ensured that the barrier side was facing in. The first few attempts didn't work because the radiation wasn't a normal form of light, but it didn't take long to create a version that stopped all forms of light."

Aubrey nodded, thinking it through. With a sudden frown, he hastily flipped open the briefing packet that he'd been clutching, and paged through to the information on Transfiguration. He ran one finger down the text until he got to the bit he'd half-remembered. "It says here that Transfiguration isn't permanent," he said accusingly. "How did turning the radioactive dirt into something else solve the problem?"

Dumbledore smiled tolerantly. "We Transfigured the affected earth into ice—we were careful to place containment charms around it first in case any of it sublimated. Fawkes and I then transported it to a volcano in Antartica. I Finited the incantation before I threw it in, of course, so the dirt melted instead of the ice evaporating. It took quite a large number of trips—as I said, time-consuming but not difficult."

Aubrey was silent, stroking his beard while staring into the distance glassy-eyed. "That's...amazing. Have you considered using this in other applications? Chernobyl, Three Mile Island...don't know how much radiation remains there, but still..."

Dumbledore nodded. "Indeed. We've had orders from the British government to aid in waste disposal from nuclear reactors. The Americans have also requested help in eliminating the contents of several of their nuclear waste repositories, and we're expecting more requests as time goes on. Now that we have established an exchange rate between Galleons and pounds sterling we are discovering that radioactive waste disposal is quite profitable; a large number of wizards and witches are setting themselves up in the business. So many, in fact, that the Ministry has had to pass emergency laws requiring that wizards and witches demonstrate minimal competence in radiation-related science before being allowed to do the job."

Aubrey nodded, stunned. "You can block all forms of radiation." He cocked his head in thought. "That's...huge. And you said the initial versions blocked some wavelengths but not others? When the light hits the surface, does it bounce off, route around, disappear—what?"

Dumbleore frowned. "I'm not really sure...I suppose we can test it somehow."

Aubrey nodded, excitement growing. "This isn't even my field, but you really need to get with some optics guys...maybe lasers..." He shook his head. "Anyway, not right now. My thing is where computers and biology intersect; I've been thinking a lot about life extension lately, and I saw something in the packet about a cloak that keeps you from dying?"

"Okay, let's try this again," Pat said, speaking carefully. "Xare, please don't actually go anywhere. Just tell me: are you able to teleport with people when Hermione doesn't come along?"

The firebird bobbed her head, giving him a look that combined curiosity and patience.

"She teleported with me and about fifty other people, sir," Hermione offered. "Mostly children, but a few adults. We all needed to be in contact, but we found a spell that could connect us even if we weren't physically touching. Also, anything she's carrying gets lighter."

"Lighter, huh?" Eric asked. Having had a practical demonstration of Xare's abilities, the interview had now expanded to include most of the department heads, and the head of Payload Systems was always interested in how to reduce weight. "How much can she carry?"

The bird looked at him, looked at Hermione, and seemed to sigh. Caw! she said.

Hermione smiled and scratched Xare's breast feathers. "I know, but if the mission is to take humanity to the stars—or even just the Moon—then we need to answer the questions first."

Caw! The sound was almost grumpy. Pat could almost understand it himself—why can't we just go? I'll take you right now!

"It would be nice if it were that easy," John said gruffly. "What would we do if you weren't there? We need to be able to do this on our own, even if you aren't available."

Xare gave an irritable huff. Spreading her wings just slightly, she hopped from Hermione's shoulder to John's desk. The thing was institutional metal and the drawers were loaded with paper files—John used electronic storage, but he preferred to look at paper instead of a screen. It weighed easily several hundred pounds; Xare sank her claws into the edge and flapped, rising into the air and hovering with the desk effortlessly suspended below her. She looked at them calmly for a moment, then disappeared, reappearing on the other side of the room with a smug look on her avian face and the desk still suspended in her claws like it weighed no more than a feather. One more teleport and she returned the desk to its original spot.

"Wow. That's going to simplify launch," Mark said, goggle-eyed. The head of Launch Control, he believed in the dream too much to worry about the fact that both he and his entire department had just been made largely redundant.

"Okay," Pat said slowly, his brain ticking along. "So, she can teleport to the moon, she can bring a huge number of people and cargo along...we just need some life support. How would a suit handle being teleported? Or maybe we put together a vehicle?"

"Speaking of vehicles, could we use her to deploy a re-supply a space station? Because I've been thinking about O'Neill wheels..."

"Not a good plan," John said, shooting him a glance. "Even if she could deploy it, you wouldn't want her resupplying it. See that flash of fire when she emerges? It would do bad things to anything she came out next to, and it would use up a bunch of the oxygen."

"How do you know?" Eric demanded. "She's on fire right now, but she's not burning anything."

John glared back. "Fire still needs oxygen, you—"

"Aaand we're breathing," Mark said, interrupting quickly before the two could really get started on the latest round of their feud. "We're all calm, rational adults. So, we can do tests to see if the fire is dangerous. Xare says she can transfer with people other than Hermione, so we should be able to send astronauts up—"

Caaaaaw! Xare said, glaring at Mark.

"I'm sorry sir, but I don't think she's willing," Hermione said, embarrassed. "She says that she's able to, but that I'm her person. I think she wouldn't mind doing it occasionally, or in an emergency, but I don't think she wants to make it a regular thing."

They all looked at her, looked at the bird, and sighed in perfect sync.

"Lovely," John growled. "All right, we can cut a suit down easily enough, but we'll still want a vehicle. I'm not letting anyone send a young girl into space with nothing but a suit." The others nodded in perfect agreement.

"Is this right?" Nancy asked, tapping a finger on the page of the briefing packet that she'd shuffled to the top. "You can make a potion that grants perfect luck?" She carefully kept the growl out of her voice; Slughorn was a tidy, fat little package of everything she disliked—smug, smooth in an oily way, clearly out for himself, and probably a lying weasel—but she'd work with a used car salesman if it could do what this man apparently could, and she knew enough not to irritate a potential co-author...or, in this case, potion supplier.

He nodded in that irritatingly smug way. "Indeed," he said with a pleased smile. "Although the stuff doesn't just make luck, it only concentrates it. Whatever good luck it gives you, you'll have an equal amount of bad luck after it wears off." He smiled slyly, taking a sip of his tea before continuing. "It's also quite difficult to brew, however. I am, if I may say so, the only one to successfully manage the trick in twenty years. I daresay there's no one else right now who can do it."

She nodded crisply. "I looked it up," she said, waving vaguely at the giant wall of books. "Didn't seem terribly complicated; takes six months, but the directions seem straightforward. What's so hard about it?"

"It's very sensitive," he said calmly. "You'll ruin it if you do anything even slightly wrong—get it the tiniest bit too hot or too cold, wave your wand in a figure eight that isn't completely flat, or that doesn't completely close, or that overlaps itself at all. Everything needs to go exactly right, or you end up with something that looks and smells exactly like Liquid Luck but is in fact incredibly toxic." He smiled. "And, before you ask, if you're under the effects of Liquid Luck when you try to brew Liquid Luck...bad things happen. It was invented by Zygmunt Budge in June of 1594; in May of 1595, Bartomias Bettleborough tried to use a small amount to make a larger batch. He lived in a small town at the foot of a mountain a bit east of Pereira, Colombia; the town isn't there anymore."

"Hm," she said, narrowing her eyes. "You do this in a cauldron, right? Big heavy metal thing, probably cast iron? Not necessarily uniform thickness or metal quality? And you heat it over a fire made with wood, right? When you say 'tiniest bit' too hot or too cold it can't really be that precise. I would imagine your average chemist could do rather better."

He chuckled and sipped his ridiculously expensive Scotch. "You and your chemists are certainly welcome to try, my dear. I doubt you've be successful without a wand, though."

"Hmph." She pondered for a minute. "Does it need a powerful wizard? Are some wizards stronger than others, or do they just know more?"

He took another sip of the tea, then paused and studied the mug. "You know, when Mr. Potter approached me about coming to this event and answering questions, I must admit that I wasn't terribly keen on the idea. He was, however, quite persuasive." He swirled the tea thoughtfully, not looking up. "I didn't expect there to be quite so many questions, though."

Nancy Keller was, by choice, bluff and direct to the point of rudeness. Despite that, she hadn't made it in academia without learning to follow subtext or play the political game. She painted a smile on her face and forced a rueful laugh. "Ah, I'm sorry, Professor. It's just so fascinating, you know? So many new things to learn, and I find potion-making especially fascinating, since it ties in so well with my own work. Tell me, what got you interested in it?"

She kept the smile on her face and the sigh inaudible while she waited for the old blowhard to get enough of listening to his own voice that they could get back to productive work. Meanwhile, she allowed her thoughts to wander to ways of automating some of this apparently complicated process. A lot of what she did relied on taking samples until you happened to get a viable gene string; if you could cheat, and make yourself so lucky that you always got a viable string on the first try...well now.

"So, you can actually bring dead people back and talk to them?" Alexi asked with carefully curbed excitement. "Can you bring anyone back?"

Harry nodded. "Yes. Whoever is operating the stone needs to have a personal connection with the spirit they want to bring back, so it's generally not practical to bring back anyone who died more than a few decades ago. Aside from that, yes. Anyone."

"Boize moi," Alexi murmured, his eyes fogging over in shock. After a moment he looked back at Harry with eager intent. "Einstein? Hilbert? Volterra? Hardy? Von Neuman? Rutherford?" His voice dropped to a reverent whisper. "Erdös?"

Harry chuckled. "Yes, sir. You're actually the third person to ask me about this today. Apparently the opportunity to gain an Erdös number of one is rather exciting. Be aware, though, that spirits know everything they knew in life but they can't change their minds about anything. Also, they learn rather slowly."

Alexi nodded, ignoring the warnings because he was too excited to speak, much less pay attention.

"No, I'm not joking," David growled. "This isn't a prank, my son legitimately has a phoenix, just like that girl in the news. I've already seen it tele—hello? Hello?"

With a snarl, he slammed the phone down and glared at it as though it were personally responsible for his frustration.

"No luck, Dad?" Joel asked quietly from the wing-backed armchair beside him. Peri was perched on the back of the chair, head cocked in consideration.

David rubbed his face. "No," he sighed. "Every number at NASA I could find and our Senator—apparently they've all been getting a lot of prank calls."

Caw! Peri cried, mantling fiercely. Go! Protect! Exalt! Bring all our brethren to the stars! rang the echo of the bird's call, bouncing through the depths of their souls.

"Peri, we want to, we just don't know how," Joel said, his voice pained. "I know that if we could just get to someone with the power to move things, we could make it work, but I don't know...who..." He trailed off, staring into space for a minute.

"Got an idea?" his father asked. He felt the bird's cry himself; it drove him to succeed, to do whatever it took, without question or concern for the cost. He was eager to answer the call, but the only idea he had left was to put them in the car and drive to Congressional Hill directly. It was thirteen hours, and he'd need to call in sick to work for at least two days, which could cause him problems—he was out of sick days after a bad round of pneumonia earlier in the year—but the call of a phoenix made it seem a trivial sacrifice.

"Well...what about President Bush?" Joel said slowly.

David winced; if only the phoenix had come in just a few more months! Of all the Presidents to have in office at a time like this...

"He could get us whatever we need, right Dad? And Peri could take us directly to him!"

The bird shook its head regretfully. Caw, it said.

Joel's face fell. "Oh. Only places and people that I've seen? Okay."

David frowned; as much as he could wish that the office were held by anyone else, the President really could open all the needed doors. "Do you need to have seen them personally?" he asked. "If you've just seen them on TV, would that be enough?"

Peri stared at him, first with one eye, then with the other. The expression of non-comprehension came through clearly.

Joel, on the other hand, was already running for the remote and turning the channel to C-SPAN.

"So, Professor," Robert began. "Aubrey was telling me that you built this entire castle in a week?"

Dumbledore nodded. "Indeed. It needed a hundred of the top wizards in the world—quite expensive, convincing them all to drop what they were doing for a week and Apparate over to participate in such an enormous ritual. Still, the Ministry was willing to pay." He chuckled and sipped on his pumpkin juice. "Honestly, I believe that the reason they were so excited to unknot the purse strings was because the ruin of Hogwarts was a reminder of just how badly you Muggles hurt us during the fighting. Too many wizards are still having trouble getting used to the idea that Muggle society is as advanced, or even more advanced, than our own."

Robert nodded. "Indeed. If you don't mind me asking, exactly how much did it cost?"

"Hm," Dumbledore said, frowning in thought. "I wasn't party to the negotiations, but I believe it was on the order of seven thousand Galleons for each of the other wizards—Sergei was crowing about getting paid a thousand a day."

"So, seven million Galleons, total," Robert said, frowning. "Thirty-five million dollars..." He went quiet for a moment, thinking. When he looked up his smile was wide and avaricious. "Professor Dumbledore, I believe there might be a few Muggles who would be interested in an enormous magical castle containing, among other things, a room that can be whatever they want it to be. Do you suppose that I could hire you and those other wizards for...say, one hundred thousand Galleons each?"

Dumbledore's eyebrows rose. "I thought you were here for the symposium?" he asked. "Aren't you a...'geneticist', I believe was the word?"

"Screw genetics," Robert said with fervor. "I suddenly have a hankering for real estate!"

Author's Note: I'm using the HPMOR exchange rate of 50 GBP to the Galleon instead of the canon 5:1.

In other news, this chapter was a pain in the neck to write, because I kept having to remind myself that it's set in 1992. There's no cell phones for the Space Agency folks to be using to call an ambulance, there's no ISS for Xare to endanger the oxygen of, there's no Yucca Mountain nuclear waste repository for the wizards to be cleaning up, there's no Cire Perdue for Slughorn to be sipping in order to show off his wealth, and there's no YouTube for Joel and David to be looking for pictures of the Oval Office on. Oh, and Aubrey de Grey was still working on a fruit-fly database instead of techniques for human rejuvenation. Meh; at that point in his career he likely wouldn't have been invited to the symposium, but he was my first contact with the idea of real-world rejuvenation and life extension, so he needed to be there.

Author's Footnote: I have a mailing list! It can be found at /dks-list (That's bit. do /dks-list for those of you reading on a site/device that eats links.) There is one email every two weeks, and each one includes links to new postings as well as bonus material not available on the web—world history, character studies, deleted scenes, etc.

Also, I have other stories for sale! You can find them on Amazon. (bit. do/dks-amazon-books, if you are dealing with a link-eater.)

Chapter 5

Author's Note: Ordinarily I put this in the footer, but given the ending of this chapter I choose to have nothing after it.

My mailing list can be found at bit. do /dks-list. "Squiring the Phoenix" will be concluding shortly. When it does, I will be publishing a new superheroes-in-the-real-world serial novel. List members will receive free copies of each chapter before it is posted for sale on Amazon. Due to Amazon's Terms of Service, once they are posted for sale the chapters will not be available elsewhere.

"Hang on, I must have misheard you," Toni said in disbelief. "Say that again."

Lambert Smythe frowned. "The Gemino curse creates worthless copies of an object," he obligingly repeated.

"When you say 'worthless', what exactly do you mean? Like, if you copy a piece of gold the result is made of lead or something?"

"No one would create gold," he said with a frown. "The goblins are in a permanent state of war with anyone who performs counterfeiting or tampers with the valuable metal supply."

Toni shook her head in frustration. "Argh, that's not the— Okay, fine. Forget the gold. If you duplicate...say, a diamond, is it made out of glass?"

He shook his head. "No, the copy is indistinguishable from the original in the beginning. It simply degrades fairly rapidly—in general it decomposes into dust and then to nothing within a few days."

Toni stared at him. He couldn't really be this thick, could...oh, wait. Wizards. Right. She rubbed her head for a moment in frustration.

"Will the copy possess any magical properties of the original?" she asked.

"Hm," he said thoughtfully. "I...don't actually know. So far as I'm aware, no one's ever actually checked that."

Toni gave him a narrow-eyed look. "You're pranking me, aren't you?"

"What? No, why would I do that?" he asked in apparently honest confusion. "You're paying me for consultation, and I have a reputation to maintain."

She rubbed her head again and then said, with nigh-infinite patience, "Would you please cast Gemino on your wand, and then check to see if you can cast spells with the copy?"

"I'm afraid I can't," he said. "It requires a flick of the wand at the target, and there's no way to flick a wand at itself."

"Oh," she said.

"I do have a mokeskin pouch with me, if that will suffice...?" he said.

"Yes! Absolutely, do that!"

He took something invisible off his belt, twitched his wand at it with a quick 'Gemino!' and then picked up something invisible just to the right of the invisible thing he had originally put down. He mimed opening a bag and peering in, then stuck his arm in up to the shoulder.

"Hm, fascinating!" he said. "Yes, not only did it duplicate the pouch, but all the contents as well. Here's my pipe, and my tobacco, and a copy of...erm...some reading material, and my broom...yes, everything seems to be here." He reclaimed his arm and gave her a broad smile. "Very clever indeed! Still, it's of limited use; the broom will fall apart in two or three days, so I'm better off sticking with the real one."

She sighed. "Is there any reason you can think of that smoking the duplicated tobacco would be dangerous?" she asked.

"Noooo...I don't think so," he said slowly. "The duplicates will degrade within a few days, meaning any smoke that was still in my lungs would turn to dust and then vanish. I wouldn't recommend doing it with food, or smoking duplicated tobacco on a regular basis, but there shouldn't be a harmful level of particulates left in the lungs from smoking a small amount."

"If you're sure it's safe, would you please try it?" she asked.

He shrugged, pulled a pipe and tobacco from nowhere, and lit up. "Hm, yes. Quite good," he said in approval.

"Is it the same as the original as far as you can tell?" she asked.

He nodded, extinguishing the pipe and tapping out the remaining contents, which he then Vanished. "Indeed. Still, it's a bit of a curiosity, isn't it? I wouldn't recommend smoking duplicate tobacco regularly, and the stuff is cheap enough that it's just as easy to buy it."

She took a deep breath, determined not to lose her temper. "Would you come with me, please?" She turned and led him back into the lab. Aubrey looked up and gave her a wave as she came in, then went back to what he was working on.

She led Smythe over to the cooler where the troll and unicorn blood samples were kept, and pulled out a vial of each.

"Could you please duplicate these for me?" she asked. He shrugged and did so; she took the resulting duplicates, put them in the mixer, and pressed the start button. A minute later, when the samples had been properly combined, she took the result out, loaded it into an injector, and pulled a mouse out of one of the nearest cages.

"Properly speaking, I should have a planned procedure and controls set up before doing this," she said, injecting the mixture into the mouse. "Right now, though, I just want to do a quick test to see if this idea is completely silly on the face of it."

With a scalpel from one of the drawers, she made a small incision on the mouse's left forefoot...which promptly healed closed. She set the mouse carefully back in its cage, walked silently to the autoclave to deposit her scalpel, and switched the device on.

"Wizards," she muttered.

o-o-o-o

"Please try to hold very still," the technician said.

Milly Mockleworthington lay still, happily tapping her toes together and twiddling her thumbs where her hands were folded on her stomach.

"Ma'am, please try to remain still," the technician said with admirable patience. "That means your hands and feet as well."

Milly sighed. "Oh, fine. You Muggles and your silly ideas." She sighed again and went still.

"Thank you," the technician growled, carefully pushing Mute on the mic first. With the goddamn witch finally having stopped her goddamn fidgeting he pushed the button to slide the table inside the MRI and activated the scanner.

"Gotta say, Doc," the technician said to the researcher beside him. "I'm pretty sure you're right; magic really must cause brain damage. I hope you figure out how to fix it."

o-o-o-o

Peri was on Joel's shoulder every moment now, and never stopped singing. It made life a lot more pleasant for everyone who worked with Joel; the song of the phoenix soothed away worries and frustration, made headaches vanish, temporarily suppressed the symptoms of a cold, and left people cheerful and energized for hours.

"Do you guys think it's weird that Peri sings constantly?" Karen asked. "He didn't used to, back when they first came in."

Davis shrugged. "I dunno. Maybe he's just happy because things are going so well?"

"Yeah, but...it's weird, and a little disturbing," she said. "I mean, when you're around them, you can't help but feel good. It's like the bird is shooting you up with Prozac. There's a whole question of free will here."

Davis looked at her is disbelief. "Are you seriously complaining about the fact that you're in a better mood when the bird is singing at you?"

She grimaced. "Well...I dunno, it's bothering me is all. I think next time I see him I'm going to ask him to not do it around me anymore. I'd rather be Karen, instead of being forced to be happy-cheerful-Karen all the time."

Davis shrugged. "I think you're nuts but sure, whatever. Now, can we get back to these designs? We've got a review meeting in two days and they aren't finished yet."

o-o-o-o

"Good evening, I'm Peter Jennings and you're watching ABC World News Tonight. In a surprise announcement today, China has declared that it is nationalizing its wizarding community. In the future, all Chinese wizards will be considered national assets; although they will be given all possible comforts, they will also be required to perform assignments as directed by the office of the President. In addition, they will be required to donate sperm and eggs on a regular basis in order to enlarge the national wizarding population.

"The United States, Britain, and most European nations have all raised strident objections to these policies, from both among the wizarding and mundane populations. Economic sanctions are being discussed and may go into effect as soon as next week.

"In technology news, scientists at MIT have completed analysis on the transfigured carbon nanotube samples provided by Harry Potter. The actual analysis was completed under the effects of Liquid Luck, but all results were checked afterwards under normal conditions, and they feel confident that they can go into large-scale production within three months.

"Finally, NASA has announced that the deployment of the Icarus constellation of solar power satellites has been successful. President Clinton will be onhand for a ceremony at Cape Canaveral tomorrow in order to press the button activating the satellites, after which America will be free of dependency on fossil fuels. In addition, there will be a surplus of nearly one hundred gigawatts which will be sold to Canada and Mexico. Satellite deployment will continue, and it is expected that within ten years the entire North American continent will be powered exclusively from space. Elon Musk's Tesla Corporation is already building solar recharging stations around the country to take advantage of the nearly-free energy to power their new electric cars."

o-o-o-o

"Hey Karen, you wanted to see us?" Joel asked as he walked into her office and sprawled out in a chair, crossing his lanky legs at the ankle. He'd really shot up over the last eight years; the skinny teenager had been replaced with a six-foot-two young man with some serious muscle from horsing satellites around—even with Peri taking most of the weight, the things still weren't light.

Peri's liquid trills flowed through the room in a river of happiness and Karen felt the tension in her shoulders vanish.

"Yeah," she said. "I have a favor to ask. Peri, could you please stop singing for a minute?"

The bird completly ignored her.

Even through the happiness imposed by the phoenix song, Karen frowned. This wasn't right; Peri was a very cooperative person. He worked smoothly with the rest of the team and was pretty much always willing to donate a feather for study, shift heavy equipment around, or whatever else they needed. Occasionally someone would ask for something unreasonable just as a joke and he would give them a look of disgust and a flip of the feathers, but she couldn't think of a time when he'd refused a reasonable request.

Joel shrugged. "Sorry, Karen. He just seems happy these days; I think it's because things are going so well with the program. We're really making a difference. You know we can't exactly communicate in words, but he feels kind of...smug...about the fact that he and his person have done more to help humanity than any other phoenix ever." He smiled in tolerant amusement and scritched Peri's chest feathers. "I sometimes imagine all the phoenixes getting together around the water cooler and Peri strutting up and down going 'who da man? oh yeah, it's me, it's me, oh yeah' and all the other phoenixes sighing and bowing their heads."

Karen laughed. She was sure that, even without the phoenix song, it would have been a funny image; with the song, it was hilarious. Which was sort of the problem, actually; she couldn't even trust her own sense of humor around the bird. Still, there was nothing for it; she couldn't exactly tape Peri's beak shut.

"Okay, never mind," she said. "Anyway, the final design review is being done for the Marsbase dome components and I wanted to get your input. You'll be asked to join the review committee tomorrow, but for now I want to go over things with you one-on-one to make sure that we've optimized for your carry capacity, work out the best timetable for deliveries, and generally make sure that neither of you see any issues. In addition to the components themselves, you'll be taking along a team that will do the setup while you haul new elements up. Anyway, here's the basic component design..."

o-o-o-o

"Hey big brain, any word back on the applications?" Pat asked with a grin. Based on the fact that the girl was right in the middle of her Happy Dance, he was pretty sure he knew the answer.

She brandished a fistful of envelopes at him. "I got in! I got in! I got in! Wooohooo!"

He snickered. The twenty-year-old version of Hermione was a lot more socially ept and a lot less of a spaz than her twelve-year-old self had been, but sometimes the younger Hermione still peeked out.

"And where did you get in, if I may ask?" he said with exaggerated politeness.

"Everywhere! Oxford, Cambridge, Princeton, Stanford, MIT...everywhere! Squeeeeeeee!" By now she was just vibrating in place, clutching the envelopes to her chest and bouncing up and down at super speed, so fast that Xare hopped to a nearby bookshelf with a disgruntled squawk.

He laughed. "That's lovely; you totally earned it. Now, do I need to leave you alone for a minute or do you think you can come down to Earth? Lunar City just finished digging the Gamma tunnels and—"

"Squeeeeeeeeee!"

He shook his head with a smile and went down to the lounge to get some coffee. When he came back he pushed the door opening, already saying, "Okay, so, we've got these new—"

"Squeeeeeeeeee!"

He shook his head and headed back to the lounge to drink his coffee. There were eighty new colonists waiting in the launch bay, but they could wait a little longer.

o-o-o-o

"Well, that explains a lot," Dan said, leaning back in his chair and studying the scans thoughtfully.

"So...are we really going to publish this?" Bill asked hesitantly. "I mean, what happens if the wizards find out that casting spells really does cause brain damage?"

Dan looked unhappy. "I think we have to, or the grant goes away. We can keep it dull though...title it something like Comparative Imaging of Enhanced and non-Enhanced Cerebral Tissue. Avoid using the words 'magic', 'mundane', or 'brain damage.' Maybe it can go under the radar."

"We have an obligation to tell the wizards what's happening to them, don't you think?" Bill said. "I mean, not telling them would basically be letting them hurt themselves. It would be like not telling people that asbestos is bad for them when they're breathing it every day."

Dan scrubbed at his face. "Look, I don't like it either, but this is like cold fusion—it's such a strong claim that we better be absolutely sure before we say anything. What if we're wrong? We freak people out and ruin our own reputations for nothing.

"For that matter, these results raise more questions than they answer. Why are the effects so specific? Wizards don't lose memories, or the ability to speak—they just get...wacky. Purple robes and green hats, all that stuff. And they don't see simple possibilities that are perfectly obvious. Shoot, my daughter came up with all sorts of ways to exploit Aguamenti, and she's only four. And it's not even all of them—some of the wizards are perfectly sensible, like that Potter kid who's been doing all the work in nanotube production and biogerontology, Granger over at the UKSA...even Slughorn seems pretty balanced from what I've seen at his presentations. Why does it only affect some of them? "

"Maybe it's a genetic thing?" Bill suggested. "Aren't Potter and Granger both from mundane families?"

Dan took his glasses off and scrubbed his face with both hands. "Not sure. I think I remember some article in one of the journals talking about the Slughorn family as one of the oldest in wizarding Britain, so he's probably a pureblood. And Potter was adopted; not sure what his genetic parents were. Anyway, good thought. Let's look into it. And let's do it fast; you're right that if it's true then we need to tell them all quickly."

"Yeah," Bill said unhappily. "Also, I've got a friend over at Caltech who can check our results. She'll keep it on the downlow if I ask, at least for a while."

o-o-o-o

The cave in Poland was very soothing. Nice and small, the walls almost within reach. The lanterns surrounding him lit the space quite well, banishing even the slightest trace of darkness and leaving him to study the colors of the flowstone around him.

Joel sat cross-legged, leaning back against one wall and taking deep breaths. The asteroid mining robot that he was supposed to be deploying was sitting in an abandoned warehouse in Detroit; it would be safe until he had prepared himself for being out from under the protective aura of Peri's song. The Xanax had kicked in about ten minutes ago, so it was time to get moving. His doctor said he was getting near the maximum safe dose and was looking around for a better course of treatment. For now it was enough to get him through a two-minute dump-and-go deployment, as long as he was careful to only look at the asteroid under his feet instead of at the stars around him.

o-o-o-o

"I'm sorry, Mr. Morrison is in a meeting right now," the receptionist said. "Could you please have a seat? He'll be with you shortly."

Janey shrugged. "Works for me. I'm paid by the hour; if he wants to keep me cooling my heels at a hundred bucks a minute I've got no problem with that." She dropped into one of the leather Bauhaus chairs and pulled a copy of "Harry Potter: The Philosopher's Stone" out of her backpack. Potter's biography was one of the more interesting things she'd read this year; she was excited to hear that there were supposed to be six more books.

Four thousand dollars later, the receptionist's phone buzzed with an internal call. She picked it up, listened, and responded quietly enough that Janey didn't catch the words.

Three seconds later, Morrison came bursting out of his office. "Terribly sorry to keep you waiting," he said, carefully not using her name in front of his receptionist. "I didn't realize you were here. Please, won't you join me?"

Janey made a point of folding down the corner of her page and tucking the book away before standing up, glancing pointedly at her watch, and preceding him into his office.

Once inside she was all business. "I need your signature on this," she said, pulling out two copies of a document and setting them on his desk. "It's the standard form that says that you will accept my statements under Veritaserum and absolve me of all responsibility in the event that the information has been leaked elsewhere or if it was taken from me by force and I was then Obliviated."

He read through it quickly and signed both copies. She tucked one away in her backpack and then pulled out a giant stone bowl that was far too big to fit in the pack.

"Here's the 'Sieve," she said, setting it on his desk. "It's a Gemini, so you've got one, maybe two days before it decomposes. I assume you've got the Veritaserum?"

"Yes, of course," he said, rifling his desk drawer for a small bottle and handing it to her.

She set one drop on her tongue and handed him back the bottle. "I have made no copies of the information I am about to present to you, nor have I communicated it to anyone else. So far as I am aware, what I am about to give you is the only copy of that information in existence outside of the original source. I am not a perfect Occlumens and therefore this testimony under Veritaserum may be considered reliable.

"Okay, here's the memory," she said, tapping her wand to her temple and pulling out a thin silver string. She dropped it in the bowl, and closed up her bag.

"Whatever the information is, I hope it's worth all the secrecy," she told him. "Payment is due on receipt, in cash, so I'll need that now."

"Absolutely," he said, trying not to stare in fascination at the wavering silver pool. "Just head down the hall to your right and tell my CFO the amount; he'll have the cash ready."

"Pleasure doing business with you," Janey Mnemonic said, walking out of his office.

o-o-o-o

Harry stared at the Jumbo-tron in amazement as the satellite so far above them began to extrude carbon nanotube cables from both sides. The fact that the nanotube assemblers had been designed, built, tested, and deployed in under two years was a feat of engineering that bordered on the miraculous. It would have been utterly impossible without enough Liquid Luck to make a series of eight thousand lightning bolts destroy the lab where the work had been done and everything for a mile around. All the lab workers had been killed in the process, but the data had been carefully streamed offsite in real time so none of it was lost. All the lab workers had been terminal cancer patients who understood that this was a suicide job, and the lab had carefully been built in the middle of nowhere in South Dakota with the expectation of its destruction. No matter how much collateral damage had been caused, the job had succeeded.

A cheer went up from everyone watching. It would be days before the cable actually touched down, but this was it: once the thin anchor cable had been secured, robot spinners could run additional lines up it until the resulting tower was strong enough to support thousands of tons of people and cargo, moving up and down in simple elevator cars.

For a certain segment of humanity, this was the holy grail: a space elevator. Humanity could now reach space—and, from there, the stars—without needing a phoenix.

Harry wiped away the tears and swallowed around the lump in his throat.

o-o-o-o

"Good evening, my fellow Americans." President Bush's tailors and speech coaches had done their absolute best to give him a sense of gravitas; the best they had been able to manage was 'pinched'. Still, it was the words and the actions that were needed, not charisma.

"The fall of the Twin Towers is a tragedy from which America is still reeling. Search and rescue efforts are underway, and I offer my thanks and my prayers to all the brave men and women of both the mundane and magical community who have stepped up to assist in this time of trouble. The magical healing has saved dozens of lives, for which we are eternally grateful.

"Despite all that magic and medicine can do, thousands of Americans have lost their lives and hundreds more are yet to be found. Several square miles of Manhattan are considered unsafe to live due to the potentially harmful smoke and dust fallout from the Towers. FEMA is in talks with the wizarding community to see if there is a way to clear the dust magically, although it is too soon to have an answer.

"The terrorist organization Al-Qaeda has stepped forward to claim responsibility for the act. In a recorded video message the head of the organization, Osama Bin-Laden, has declared that the attack was motivated by, and I quote, 'the alliance of the Great Satan with the devil-spawn of magic.'

Bush paused, his face tight in clearly suppressed anger.

"In the wake of the 9/11 tragedy, I authorized deployment of magical intelligence-gathering assets. Wizards employed at the CIA dispatched an owl to deliver a letter to Bin-Laden. The contents of that letter were quite simple: We are coming.

"A mixed unit of Delta Force operators followed the owl; upon discovering the location of their target the wizarding operators Side-Along Apparated their mundane cohorts into Bin-Laden's headquarters. Twenty-seven Al-Qaeda members were killed and eighteen captured, including Bin-Laden himself. As these individuals were taken as prisoners of war, our military was free to use Legilimancy to obtain critical information about the rest of the organization.

"Like most terrorist organizations, Al-Qaeda was organized as a series of cells, each of which answered to only one handler. Not even Bin-Laden himself was aware of all members of the organization.

"This did not save them. Despite their best efforts, Delta Force worked their way through the chain of handlers in under twenty-four hours. To the best of our knowledge, every single member of Al-Qaeda is either in custody or dead."

He paused, allowing those words to sink in.

"Captured members will be tried as military prisoners, meaning that they have no right to Fifth Amendment protection. They will be interrogated under Veritaserum and those admitting to terrorist crimes will be executed. Should any member of the organization be discovered who has not performed any actual acts of terror, they will be convicted as accomplices before the fact and sentenced to life imprisonment in Leavenworth Federal Penitentiary.

"In this time of sorrow, my heart goes out to all those who have lost loved ones or homes. Rest assured, I will do all that is in my power to aid you in this time of trouble. All those recovered who are injured will be given Healion at federal expense in order to fully restore them. Where we are able to recover the bodies, Congress has authorized emergency funding to perform full resurrections. As you are aware, performing a resurrection requires the assistance of someone with a close connection to the deceased. FEMA will be establishing a registry in Manhattan; anyone who has lost someone in the attack is encouraged to sign up so that we can reach you in the event that your loved one's body is recovered.

"America has taken a terrible blow this week, yet still we stand. In the face of adversity, we shall not yield. In the face of attack, we shall conquer. To all those in the world who ally themselves with Al-Qaeda or believe in their cause, I say this: Bring it on. We will do to you what we have done to the cowards that struck at innocent men and women. If you feel that your cause is worth dying for, we will be glad to help you with that.

"Thank you and good night."